Software Developer

Personal info

Name and Surname

Alejandro Rodríguez Escudero

Phone number

(+34) 662170091

alejandro.rodriguez.escu @gmail.com

Residence

Madrid - Spain

Repositories

Github

github.com/arodriguuij

Portfolio

peaceful-ardinghellid6add1.netlify.app

summary

Computer engineer focused on web development. Specialized in frontend with JavaScript and React with more than three years of experience.

In the two first companies where I have worked, I contributed to teamwork, willingness to learn and determination to provide solutions. Currently acting as a mid-senior frontend developer, decision-making and mentoring new team members.

Between the first two jobs, I took a year to improve my English. I went to UK for a year and went back in 2020, to return to work as a software engineer, which is what I am currently working on and what I am passionate about.

skills

Main skills: JavaScript / React / React Native

Others:

JavaScript libraries:

Redux (Redux-saga, Redux-thunk, Redux-reselect)

· New features:

ES9 / React-hooks

· JavaScript Testing Framework:

Jest / Enzyme

• Markup and style sheet language: html5 / css3

· Version control: Git

experience

Apr 2021 - Currently

Infoser

Web developer

Leading the frontend of Daimler's web application for data sharing between providers and consumers.

- Guiding the way for best practices and code efficiency.
- · Part of business-level decisions and their implications for web development.
- · React, javascript, redux, material-ui.
- · Mentoring front-end team members.
- Breaking down features and epics into small user stories.

Jun 2020 - Apr 2021

Zerintia Technologies

Madrid, Spain

Madrid, Spain

Web developer

Creating systems for the integration of the physical and digital worlds of industrial companies.

- · Creating systems for the integration of the physical and digital worlds of industrial companies.
- Using React as a programming language.
- Working under agile methodology

Jun 2017 - Nov 2018

Amarís

Madrid, Spain

Web developer

I contributed to the development of the account creation process of the ING bank.

- · Working on the implementation and improvement of the account creation process through the responsive web and mobile application
- · Using JavaScript as a programming language. Supported with BackboneJs
- Working under agile methodology

education

Sep 2013 – June 2017 **Degree in Software Engineering Specialization:** Model-driven engineering. Polytechnic School. University of Extremadura, Spain

main personal projects

Mar 2020 - Nowadays **applestore**

Device store shows how React components and Redux can be used to build a friendly user experience with instant visual updates and scaleable code in ecommerce applications.

• Built With: React / React-hooks / Redux / Redux-saga / ES9 / Jest / Enzyme